Guide to the Herbert Aptheker Papers, 1842-1999, (bulk 1934-1994)
Department of Special Collections
- Series 6. William Edward Burghardt Du Bois Papers
  - Subseries F. Subject files
    - Festschrift (Box 180, Folder 39)
    - Fisk University (Box 180, Folder 40)
    - Frederick Douglas Interracial Forum (Box 180, Folder 41)
    - Garvey, Marcus (Box 181, Folder 1)
    - Georgia (Box 181, Folder 2)
    - Ghandi, Mahatma (Box 181, Folder 3)
    - Hope, John (Box 181, Folder 4)
    - Howard University (Box 181, Folder 5)
    - Alphaeus Hunton: the unsung valiant / by Dorothy Hunton. -- New York: Eppress Speed Print,, n.d. (Box 181, Folder 6)
    - Illinois (Box 181, Folder 7)
    - Indo-China (Box 181, Folder 8)
    - Inferiority (Box 181, Folder 9)
    - International Institute for Afro-American Studies (Box 181, Folder 10)
    - Johnson, Charles S. (Box 181, Folder 11)
    - Jones, Jesse (Box 181, Folder 12)
    - Korea (Box 181, Folder 13)
    - Ku Klux Klan (Box 181, Folder 14)
    - Labor (Box 181, Folder 15)
    - Labor Party (Box 181, Folder 16)
    - Land grant colleges (Box 181, Folder 17)
    - League of Colored Peoples (Box 181, Folder 18)
    - Lewis case (Box 181, Folder 19)
    - Lincoln, Nebraska (Box 181, Folder 20)
    - Lynching (Box 181, Folder 21)
    - Milholland, John E. (Box 181, Folder 22)
    - Military (Box 181, Folder 23)
    - Minorities (Box 181, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 181, Folder 25)
    - Morehouse College (Box 181, Folder 26)
    - The Nation (Box 181, Folder 27)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (Box 181, Folder 28)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. Springarn Medal (Box 181, Folder 29)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. Springarn (Box 181, Folder 30)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. The branch bulletin. -- Vol. 1, nos. 3, 6-7, 10, 12; Vol. 2, nos. 1, 12; Vol. 3, no. 3; Vol. 4, nos. 4, 7-10; Vol 5, no. 5 (Box 181, Folder 31)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. The branch bulletin. -- Vol. 1, nos. 3, 6-7, 10, 12; Vol. 2, nos. 1, 12; Vol. 3, no. 3; Vol. 4, nos. 4, 7-10; Vol 5, no. 5 (Box 181, Folder 32)
    - National Guard (Box 181, Folder 33)
    - National Lawyers Guild (Box 181, Folder 34)
    - National Negro-American Political League (Box 181, Folder 35)
    - National Party (Box 181, Folder 36)
    - The Negro and crime (Box 182, Folder 1)
    - Negro Forum Council (Box 182, Folder 2)
    - Negro history (Box 182, Folder 3)
    - Negro History Week (Box 182, Folder 4)
    - Negro intelligence (Box 182, Folder 5)
    - Negro Week (Box 182, Folder 6)
    - Niagra Movement (Box 182, Folder 7)
    - Pan-African Congress (Box 182, Folder 8)
    - Peace (Box 182, Folder 9)
    - Race (Box 182, Folder 10)
    - Race relations (Box 182, Folder 11)
    - Randolph, A. Philip (Box 182, Folder 12)
    - Reference books (Box 182, Folder 13)
    - Religion (Box 182, Folder 14)
    - Republican Party (Box 182, Folder 15)
    - Riots (Box 182, Folder 16)
    - Scottsboro (Box 182, Folder 17)
    - Slavery (Box 182, Folder 18)
    - South Africa (Box 182, Folder 19)
    - Southern Regional Council (Box 182, Folder 20)
    - Speeches (Box 182, Folder 21)
    - St. John's (Box 182, Folder 22)
    - Storer College (Box 182, Folder 23)
    - Suffrage (Box 182, Folder 24)
    - Testimony (Box 182, Folder 25)
    - Theater (Box 182, Folder 26)
    - Toledo (Box 182, Folder 27)
    - United Nations (Box 182, Folder 28)
    - Universal military training (Box 182, Folder 29)
    - Voting (Box 182, Folder 30)
    - Waldorft-Astoria Peace meeting (Box 182, Folder 31)
    - Wallace, Henry (Box 182, Folder 32)
    - War (Box 182, Folder 33)
    - Washington, Booker T. (Box 182, Folder 34)
    - West Indies (Box 182, Folder 35)
    - Who's Who (Box 182, Folder 36)
    - Women (Box 182, Folder 37)
    - World War II (Box 182, Folder 38)
    - Y.M.C.A. / Y.W.C.A. (Box 182, Folder 39)
    - Youth (Box 182, Folder 40)
  - Subseries G. Research materials
    - Arnett, B.W. The Black laws: speech in the Ohio House of Representatives, 1886 Mar. 10 (Box 182, Folder 41)
    - Boosey, T. A vindication of the use of sugar, the produce of the West-India Islands. -- 2nd ed. -- London: s.n.,, 1792 (Box 182, Folder 42)
    - Bowler, Pat. Colour bar. -- Reprinted from the Barnes and Mortlake Herald, 1926 Aug. 14 (Box 182, Folder 43)
    - Bragg, George F. The first Negro organization: the Free African Society, established on April 12th, 1787. -- Baltimore: s.n.,, 1924 (Box 182, Folder 44)
    - Candace, Gratien. Le Deuxieme Congres de la Race Noire en 1921. -- Paris: Editions de Colones et Marine,, 1921 (Box 182, Folder 45)
    - Crummell, Alexander. Civilization, the primal need of the race. The attitude of the American mind toward the Negro intellect. -- (The American Negro Academy, Occasional Papers, no. 3). -- Washington, D.C.: The Academy,, 1898 (Box 182, Folder 46)
    - Dancy, John C. Lessons from the life of Dr. J.C. Price, 1899 May 25, tms (11 p.) (Box 182, Folder 47)
    - Debs, Eugene. The color question. -- (Wilshire leaflet, no. 25). -- New York: Wilshire Book Co.,, [ca. 1908] (Box 182, Folder 48)
    - Douglass, Frederick. I bow to no priests: autograph letter signed, Rochester, to Mr. Koehler, 1870 June 14 (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - Dunbar, J.F. Liberia, a commonwealth of a peculiar character: its opportunities and its responsibilities: an oration delivered in the M.E. Church, Harper, 1909 July 26 (Box 183, Folder 2)
    - Hill, Mozell. Basic racial attitudes toward whites in the Oklahoma all-Negro community. -- In American Journal of Sociology. -- Vol. 44, no. 6, 1944 May (Box 183, Folder 3)
    - Hunton, Alphaeus. Africa fights for freedom. -- New York: Council on African Affairs, 1950 Mar. (Box 183, Folder 4)
    - League of Small and Subject Nationalities, Inc., 1917 - 1918 (Box 183, Folder 5)
    - Lenin, [V.I.]. A new letter to the workers of Europe and America. -- Brooklyn: The Socialist Publication Society,, 1919 (Box 183, Folder 6)
    - Lenin, V.I. The Soviets at work: the International Position of the Russian Soviet Republic and the fundamental problem of the socialist revolution. -- 4th ed. -- New York: Rand School of Social Sciences,, 1918 (Box 183, Folder 7)
    - Mayo, A.D. The opportunity and obligation of the educated class of the Colored race in the Southern States: address at Agricultural and Mechanical College for Negroes, Normal, Alabama, 1899 May 29 (Box 183, Folder 8)
    - Morpeau, Moravia. L'Inconstitutionnalite de la Convention Americans-Haitienne: discours pronounce par Monsieur Moravia Morpeau a la seance du Senat du 11 Novembre 1915. -- Port-au-Prince: Imprimerie Saint-Jacques,, 1915 (Box 183, Folder 9)
    - National Afro-American Council, Washington, D.C., 1903 Feb. 2 (Box 183, Folder 10)
    - National Convention of Colored Men, Louisville, Ky: Hon. Frederick Douglass, President, 1883 Sept. 24 (Box 183, Folder 11)
    - The Negro problem. Senate Document, no. 36, 62nd Congress, 1st Session, 1911 May 23 (Box 183, Folder 12)
    - On the indictment of W.E.B. Du Bois and Peace Information Center, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 13)
    - Padmore, George, ed. The voice of Colored labour: speeches and reports of colonial delegates to the World Trade Union Conference - 1945. -- Manchester: Panaf Service, Ldt.,, 1945 (Box 183, Folder 14)
    - Peace, freedom, and abundance: the platform of the Progressive Party, 1948 July 23-25 (Box 183, Folder 15)
    - President Lincoln's views: an important letter on the principles involved in the Vallandigham case: correspondence in relation to the Democratic meeting, Albany, N.Y. -- Philadelphia: King and Baird Printers,, 1863 (Box 183, Folder 16)
    - Price, J.C. Education and the race problem, 1890, tms (10 p.) (Box 183, Folder 17)
    - Price, J.C. The Negro in the last decade of the century: what he can do for himself, 1890, tms (6 p.) (Box 183, Folder 18)
    - Price, Joseph C. The race-problem in America, 1888, tms (8 p.) (Box 183, Folder 19)
    - Proceedings of the Convention of Colored Men, Parson, KS, 1882 Apr. 27-28 (Box 183, Folder 20)
    - Race relations in the United States: the Negro's intolerable condition pointed out by Professor Du Bois and other eminent Afro-Americans. Dr. Washington's optimistic utterances repudiated. An appeal to England and Europe. -- New York: National Negro Committee,, 1910 Oct. 26, (cy 1) (Box 183, Folder 21)
    - Race relations in the United States: the Negro's intolerable condition pointed out by Professor Du Bois and other eminent Afro-Americans. Dr. Washington's optimistic utterances repudiated. An appeal to England and Europe. -- New York: National Negro Committee,, 1910 Oct. 26, (cy 2) (Box 183, Folder 22)
    - Sheppard, Wheeler. Second part of mistakes by Dr. W.E.B. Du Bois, being an answer to Dr. W.E.B. Du Bois's (so-called) reply. -- Pittsburg: Golden-Rod Printing,, 1921 (Box 183, Folder 23)
    - Smythe, Hugh H. The concept 'Jim Crow'. -- In Social Foces. -- Vol. 27, no. 1, 1948 Oct. (Box 183, Folder 24)
    - The Star of Ethiopia: a pageant, 1915 - 1925 (Box 183, Folder 25)
    - U.S. Army in World War II: the employment of Negro troops, draft of Chapter I: between two World Wars, n.d., tms (72 p.) (Box 183, Folder 26)
    - U.S. Supreme Court. The case of Dred Scott in the United States Supreme Court with the full opinions of Chief Justice Taney and Justice Curtis and abstracts of the opinions of the other judges; with an analysis of the points ruled, and some concluding observation. -- New York: Horace Greeley Co.,, 1857 (Box 183, Folder 27)
    - The utilization of Negro infantry platoons in white companies: a report of interviews with white officer and enlisted personnel in 7 infantry divisions. -- (Report no. ETO-82, copy no. 9). -- European Theater of Operations. Information and Education Division. Research Branch,, 1945 June (Box 183, Folder 28)
    - Victor, Lewis. The only way. -- Chicago: United Pioneers of 1941, Inc.,, 1944 Dec. (Box 183, Folder 29)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison. The objects of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People: address at the Fourth Annual Conference of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Chicago, 1912 (Box 183, Folder 30)
    - W.E.B. Du Bois notes, n.d. (Box 183, Folder 31)
    - Index of The crisis: a record of the darker races / W.E.B. Du Bois, ed. -- Vol. 35, 1928 (Box 183, Folder 32)
    - The Fisk Herald / W.E.B. Du Bois, ed. -- Vol. 33, no. 2, 1925 (Box 183, Folder 33)
    - Lawyers Guild Review. -- Vol. 16, no. 2, 1956 Summer (Box 183, Folder 34)
    - The Negro Quarterly. -- Vol. 1, no. 1, 1942 Spring (Box 183, Folder 35)
      Includes Slavocracy's system of control / by Herbert Aptheker. -- p. 45-71
    - The Non-Slaveholder. -- Vol. 1, no. 1, 1846 Jan. (Box 183, Folder 36)
    - Proceedings of the First Convocation of the Colored Clergy of the Protestant Episcopal Church. -- New York: Church of the Holy Communion,, 1883 Sept. 12-14 (Box 183, Folder 37)
    - A proposed solemn memorial on the tercentenary of the transplanting of the Ngro race to the United States, 1919 Aug. (Box 183, Folder 38)
    - Seeking a way: biennial report of The American Missionary Association Division of the Board of Home Missions of the Congregational and Christian Churches for 1942-1944, 1944 (Box 183, Folder 39)
    - Survey of Negroes in Little Rock and North Little Rock. -- Little Rock, Ark.: Urban League of Greater Little Rock,, 1941 (Box 183, Folder 40)
- Series 7. Audiovisual materials
  - Aptheker - Du Bois, San Francisco, 1968 Feb. 18, 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 1)
  - Speaking freely: Dr. Herbert Aptheker, 1979 Dec. 23, 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 2)
  - Herbert Aptheker - Anti-Sovietism & the U.S. national interests,, 1981 Jan., 1 sound cassette (42 min.): analog (Box 184, Folder 3)
  - Herbert Aptheker - should the Nazis & the KKK be outlawed?, 1980 Dec., 1 sound cassette (28 min.): analog (Box 184, Folder 3)
  - Herbert Aptheker: Korean incidence: address,, 1983 Sept. 7, 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 4)
  - Proletarian literature, no. 1 / Aptheker, 1988 May 18, 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 5)
  - The case of affirmative action, Sun Room, MU - ISU / Herbert Aptheker, 1990 Oct. 11, 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 6)
  - Books on air: 3 promos & Herbert,, 1990, 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 7)
  - Jean Feraca w/ Herbert Aptheker: 10 a.m. -- Madison, Wisc.: Wisconsin Public Radio,, 1991 Feb. 27, 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 8)
  - Aptheker - Black history month, n.d., 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 9)
  - Aptheker - Black history month, no. 2, n.d., 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 10)
  - Aptheker - Black history month, no. 3, n.d., 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 11)
  - The confessions of Nat Turner / Brock Peters, Herbert Aptheker, n.d., 1 sound cassette: analog (Box 184, Folder 12)
  - What's happening? Part 1-4 / Herbert Aptheker, n.d., 1 sound cassette: analog + 1 ans (Box 184, Folder 13)
  - The confession of Nat Turner as made to T.R. Gray, November 1, 1831 / read by Brock Peters. -- (Afro-American history: past and present, no. CMS 539). -- New York: CMS Records,, 1968, 1 sound disc: analog; 12 in. (Box 184)
  - Article on W.E.B. Du Bois & Pan African Congress, n.d., 1 microfilm reel: b & w; 35 mm. (Box 184, Folder 1)
  - Radio talk 1966, 1 sound tape reel (Box 184, Folder 1)
  - Radio talk 1966, 1 sound tape reel (Box 184, Folder 2)
- Series 8. Documentary History of the Negro People in the United States
  - Citadel Pres. Royalty statements for A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, 1954 - 1955 (Box 185, Folder 1)
  - Aptheker, H. Research notes for A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1 [1 of 4], n.d. (Box 185, Folder 2)
  - Aptheker, H. Research notes for A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1 [2 of 4], n.d. (Box 185, Folder 3)
  - Aptheker, H. Research notes for A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1 [3 of 4], n.d. (Box 185, Folder 4)
  - Aptheker, H. Research notes for A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1 [4 of 4], n.d. (Box 185, Folder 5)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: pp. 1-38, ca. 1950, ams (Box 185, Folder 6)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: pp. 39-130, ca. 1950, ams (Box 185, Folder 7)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: pp. 131-210, ca. 1950, ams (Box 185, Folder 8)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: pp. 211-300, ca. 1950, ams (Box 185, Folder 9)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: pp. 301-404, ca. 1950, ams (Box 185, Folder 10)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: pp. 405-510, ca. 1950, ams (Box 185, Folder 11)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: pp. 511-620, ca. 1950, ams (Box 185, Folder 12)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: pp. 621-730, ca. 1950, ams (Box 185, Folder 13)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: pp. 731-830 + unnumbered, ca. 1950, ams (Box 186, Folder 1)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: pp. B - D, ca. 1950, ams (Box 186, Folder 2)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 1: notes, ca. 1950, an (Box 186, Folder 3)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. II: index, outline, n.d. (Box 186, Folder 4)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. II: dust jacket, n.d. (Box 186, Folder 5)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. III: contract, 1968 (Box 186, Folder 6)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. Research notes for A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. III [1 of 3], ca. 1968 (Box 186, Folder 7)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. Research notes for A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. III [2 of 3], ca. 1968 (Box 186, Folder 8)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. Research notes for A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. III [3 of 3], ca. 1968 (Box 186, Folder 9)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. IV: From the end of World War II through 1959: working notes, title page, intro, table of contents, postscript, n.d. (Box 186, Folder 10)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 1-49a, ca. 1990, tms (Box 186, Folder 11)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 50-104, ca. 1990, tms (Box 186, Folder 12)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 105-154, ca. 1990, tms (Box 186, Folder 13)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 155-204, ca. 1990, tms (Box 186, Folder 14)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 204A-277, ca. 1990, tms (Box 186, Folder 15)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 278-339, ca. 1990, tms (Box 186, Folder 16)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 340-360H, ca. 1990, tms (Box 187, Folder 1)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 361-428, ca. 1990, tms (Box 187, Folder 2)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 429-483, ca. 1990, tms (Box 187, Folder 3)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 484-545, ca. 1990, tms (Box 187, Folder 4)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 546-602, ca. 1990, tms (Box 187, Folder 5)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 603-645, ca. 1990, tms (Box 187, Folder 6)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 646-700, ca. 1990, tms (Box 187, Folder 7)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 701-770, ca. 1990, tms (Box 187, Folder 8)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 771-836, ca. 1990, tms (Box 187, Folder 9)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 5: pp. 837-901, ca. 1990, tms (Box 187, Folder 10)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 1-67, n.d., tms (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 68-130, n.d., tms (Box 188, Folder 2)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 131-182, n.d., tms (Box 188, Folder 3)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 183-246, n.d., tms (Box 188, Folder 4)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 247-293, n.d., tms (Box 188, Folder 5)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 294-353, n.d., tms (Box 188, Folder 6)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 354-423, n.d., tms (Box 188, Folder 7)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 424-488, n.d., tms (Box 188, Folder 8)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 489-534, n.d., tms (Box 188, Folder 9)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 534A-606, n.d., tms (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 607-653, n.d., tms (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 654-712, n.d., tms (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 713-770, n.d., tms (Box 189, Folder 4)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 771-821, n.d., tms (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 822-888A, n.d., tms (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 889-943, n.d., tms (Box 189, Folder 7)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 944-1002, n.d., tms (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, ed. A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, Vol. 7: pp. 1003-1021, n.d., tms (Box 189, Folder 9)